2018年2月6日
On the 6th of February 2018
重型猎鹰火箭将一辆特斯拉跑车和一个叫Starman的小人送入太空
the Falcon Heavy launched Starman in a Tesla Roadster into space.
在这举世瞩目的事件中，Starman环绕了地球六小时
During this spectacular event, Starman orbited the Earth for 6 hours
在重型猎鹰的二级火箭将跑车送入绕日轨道前拍摄了许多美丽的图片
capturing beautiful images before the Falcon Heavy upper stage sent the car into an orbit around the sun.
可现在Starman到哪了？
But where is Starman now?
我们还会再见吗？
And will we ever see him again?
本期视频，我们将了解Starman离开地球后的漫漫征程
In this video, we’re going to look at the long journey Starman has been on since leaving Earth.
我们还将了解他将何时回到地球
We’re also going to look at when he might return to Earth
以及我们有哪些可能的办法将他带回来
and the possible solutions we have for retrieving him.
在Starman离开地球轨道后
After Starman left Earth’s orbit,
全世界的科学家和天文爱好者都把望远镜指向了夜空
scientists and amatuer astronomers around the world pointed their telescopes towards the night sky
来追踪跑车并预测它未来的轨道
in order to track the Roadster and predict its future orbit.
Jet Propulsion Laboratory，喷气推进实验室
JPL的一伙人利用SpaceX提供的数据预测
A team at JPL used data provided by SpaceX and predicted
Starman将会在2091年再次飞临地球
that Starman would pass by Earth in the year 2091,
最近将只有几千公里
getting within a few thousand kilometers.
这个预测模型前几个月是准确的
This model proved to be accurate for the first few months,
但由于其使用的数据非常有限
but since it was made from a limited amount of data,
之后的误差将逐渐增加
anything beyond that became increasingly inaccurate.
直到今年三月我们才得到Starman未来更准确的预测
It wasn’t until March of this year that we got a solid prediction of Starman’s future.
这要归功于位于南非的一个观察到那辆跑车的望远镜
Thanks to an observation of the Roadster seen from a telescope in South Africa,
让JPL能修正他们的测量并准确预测Starman未来50年的轨迹
JPL were able to refine their measurements and accurately predict Starman’s path for the next 50 years.
他们得出结论：Starman将在2020年飞越火星
They concluded that Starman is on a path that will pass by Mars in the year 2020,
最近距离450万英里(约720万公里)
getting within 4.5 million miles.
人类目前在火星的望远镜无法观测这个距离下像跑车那样小的物体
At this point, the current telescopes we have on Mars won’t be capable of observing an object as dim as the Roadster.
在2035年，Starman将会更近地接近火星
Starman will make a closer approach to Mars in the year 2035,
最近距离150万英里(约240万公里)
getting as close as 1.5 million miles.
到那时，人类在火星表面和火星轨道上很可能会有更先进的望远镜
By then, it’s likely that we’ll have more advanced telescopes on and around Mars
来拍摄那辆跑车的照片
to capture an image of the Roadster,
即使它只是天空中一个小点
even if it’s just a tiny dot in the sky.
Starman将会在2047年达到与地球的最近距离
Starman will make its closest approach to Earth in the year 2047,
在300万英里处飞越(约480万公里)
passing by at just 3 million miles.
地球上的望远镜将有能力观测到那辆跑车
At this distance, telescopes on Earth will be able to observe the Roadster
记录下它在太空中的位置
and record its position in the sky,
以供我们重新修正对其未来若干年的轨道预测
giving us a more refined prediction for many years to come.
但如果我们有能力在这次接近中捕获Starman呢？
But what if we were able to catch Starman during this close approach?
太空中捕获卫星并不新鲜
The idea of retrieving satellites from space isn’t unheard of.
航天飞机有巨大的载荷舱
Due to the enormous payload bay on the Space Shuttle,
能够把故障卫星捕获并带回地球
it was capable of retrieving faulty satellites and returning them to back to Earth.
STS-51共有STS-51、STS-51-A、C、D、B、G、F、I、J、L十次任务
视频中指的是STS-51-A任务
在STS-51-A任务中，宇航员成功使用EVA喷气背包与航天飞机机械臂
During STS-51, astronauts managed to grapple two communication satellites into the payload bay
将两颗通信卫星(Westar 6和Palapa B2)捕获并放进载荷舱
using EVA jetpacks and the Shuttle’s robotic arm.
这些卫星返回地球后卖给了新的客户
Those satellites were returned to Earth and sold to new customers
Westar 6后来由亚洲卫星公司购入 更名“亚洲一号”
在1990年4月7日由长征三号火箭成功发射
并在之后重新发射进正确轨道
who relaunched them into the correct orbits.
然而把地球轨道外的卫星捕获的难度则大得多
However, retrieving satellites outside of Earth’s orbit is much more challenging
需要多得多的能量
and requires a lot more energy.
2014年日本发射的探测器(隼鸟二号)
A Japanese spacecraft which launched in 2014
步履蹒跚地终于到达了距地球1.8亿英里的小行星
has slowly made its way out to an asteroid 180 million miles from Earth.
它已经采集到小行星表面的样本
It has already managed to retrieve samples from the surface
并还将继续勘探小行星，并在2020年把样本送回地球
and it will continue to survey the asteroid before returning those samples back to Earth in 2020.
虽然特斯拉跑车是个要从太空带回来的大得多的“样本”
Although the Roadster is a much heavier sample to bring back from space,
Starship也能使用类似的方案来捕获那辆跑车
Starship could follow a similar plan to retrieve the Roadster.
拥有超大运力的Starship
With the enormous capability of Starship,
可以在近地轨道补充燃料并与跑车的轨道交会
it could refuel in Earth’s orbit and perform a maneuver to match the Roadster’s orbit.
而利用剩余的大量燃料
With a large amount of fuel remaining,
它能捕获跑车并收进载荷舱内，然后返回地球
it could then capture the Roadster and store it in the payload bay before returning to Earth.
所以或许有一天，很多年以后
So perhaps one day, many years down the line,
经历过宏伟的重型猎鹰火箭发射的那一代人
the generation that experienced the iconic Falcon Heavy launch
能够再次和Starman、和那辆跑车相会吧
will be reunited with Starman and his Roadster.
又或许，它最好的归宿是继续在太阳系流浪
Or perhaps, it’s best to let him wander the solar system forever
成人类文明的“吉祥物”吧
like a mascot for human civilization.
感谢Primal Space的帮助每个视频撰写文稿查找资料的赞助者
Thank you to the Primal Space patrons who helped to write and research each video.
如果你想赞助Primal Space频道并加入我们专有Discord群
If you'd like to contribute Primal Space and join our exclusive Discord.
请访问patreon.com/primalspace
please visit patreon.com/primalspace
满100名赞助者后会再抽一位赠送土星五号乐高玩具
where we will be giving away another Saturn V Lego Set once we reach 100 patrons.
所以记得关注，方便我们讨论、学习所有和太空有关的知识
So make sure you've subscribed, so you can join the discussion as we continue to learn more about all things space.
非常感谢您的观看，我们下期视频见
Thank you very much for watching, and I'll see you in the next video.